brockport.edu 2014-11-21

# Privacy Policy: The College at Brockport

### Our Commitment to Privacy

We are committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with us.  We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit our Web site.  You can travel through most of our Web site without giving us any information about yourself.  Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices. 

We do not collect any _personal information_ about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending e-mail or completing an online form.  This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

### Information Collected Automatically When You Visit Our Web Site

When visiting our Web site, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

  * The names of files the _user_ attempts to access from our Web site, including Web pages, graphics included in Web pages, PDF files, etc.
  * Any errors encountered in completing the _user's_ request
  * The date and time of the _user's_ request
  * The Web page from which the _user_ accessed the current Web page
  * The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site
  * The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute _personal information_ by the [Internet Privacy and Security Act ](http://www.oft.state.ny.us/policy/OFTEnablingLeg.htm). The information that is collected automatically is used to improve the content of our Web site and to help us understand how our _users_ are interacting with our Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our _users_.  The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and we are not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from our Web site for commercial marketing purposes.

### Information Collected When You E-mail Us or Complete a Transaction 

During your visit to our Web site, you may send e-mail to us. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected.  The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in your message.  Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your inquiry to other campus individuals for appropriate action.  Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and we are not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.

During your visit to our Web site, you may complete a transaction through an online form. The information collected by us, including _personal information_ volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by us and may be disclosed by us for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.

We do not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13.  _Users_ are cautioned, however, that the collection of _personal information_ submitted by e-mail or online form will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. 

### Disclosure of Information Collected Through Our Web Site 

The collection of information through out Web site and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act.  We will only collect _personal information_ through our Web site or disclose _personal information_ collected through our Web site if the _user_ has consented to the collection or disclosure of such _personal information_.  The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to us by the _user_ constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by us for the purposes for which the _user_ disclosed the information to us.

However, we may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform our statutory duties, or necessary for us to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the _user_ ; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.

Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through our Web site is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.  We may disclose _personal information_ to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce our rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to our information technology assets.

### Retention of Information Collected Through Our Web Site

We retain the information collected through our Web site in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the [New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law](http://home.att.net/~allanmcnyc/art_laws.html).  In general, our Internet services logs, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of our Web site, are maintained for not less than three backup cycles or the end of the budget year to facilitate departmental annual reporting, whichever is greater.  Public reports generated from the information in these logs provide only aggregate information and will remain on file indefinitely for purposes of comparison.  Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed at the end of this policy.

### Access to and Correction of _Personal Information_ Collected Through Our Web Site

Any _user_ may submit a request to our privacy compliance officer to determine whether _personal information_ pertaining to that _user_ has been collected through our Web site.  Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the _user_.  Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the _user_ , or similar appropriate identification.  The address of the privacy compliance officer can be found at the end of this policy.

The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the _personal information_ ; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.

In the event that we have collected _personal information_ pertaining to a _user_ through our Web site and that information is to be provided to the _user_ pursuant to the _user's_ request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the _user_ of his or her right to request that the _personal information_ be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in [section 95 of the Public Officers Law.](http://www.tenant.net/Other_Laws/Pubofc/pubofc08.html)

### Confidentiality and Integrity of _Personal Information_ Collected Through Our Web Site

We are strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through our Web site against unauthorized access, use or disclosure.  Consequently, we limit employee access to _personal information_ collected through our Web site to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties.  Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_.

In addition, we have implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of our information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption.  These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of our Web site as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of our Web site for all _users_ , we employ software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage our Web site.

### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the _user's_ browser on the hard drive of the _user's_ computer.  We may use cookies in the following ways:

  * to verify authorized access to Web systems that contain _personal information_ ( _e.g. Angel, Banner)_
  * to enhance or customize a _user's_ visit to our Web site ( _e.g._ to remember _user_ preferences)
  * to better understand the use of our Web site so we can better serve _users_ in the future

To protect _personal information_ , we may require _users_ to accept cookies to access certain online services.  However, we do not require the use of cookies to access any public areas of our Web site.

### Definitions

The following definitions apply to terms used in this policy.

Terms such as "us," "we," and "our" refer to The College at Brockport, State University of New York.

"Our Web site" refers to all Web pages officially maintained by us within the brockport.edu domain for our marketing efforts or to conduct our day-to-day business with our students, alumni, faculty and staff.  This term does not apply to personal or other unofficial pages unrelated to our marketing efforts or our day-to-day business.

The following terms appear in _italics_ throughout this policy:

_Personal information_ : For purposes of this policy, " _personal information_ " means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.

_User_ : shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law.

### Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through our Web site. 

### Contact Information 

For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e-mail at [privacy@brockport.edu](mailto:privacy@brockport.edu) or by regular mail at:

Privacy Compliance Officer  
SUNY Brockport ITS  
350 New Campus Dr.  
Brockport, NY  14420

Policy effective June 16, 2002.  
Amended June 10, 2009.
